smooci.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy – Smooci

## Privacy Policy

We take the privacy of our Website visitors very seriously. We ask that you read this privacy policy (Policy) carefully as it contains important information about how we will use your personal data. 

For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998, SMO-Tech (‘we’ or ‘us’) is the ‘data controller’ (ie the company who is responsible for, and controls the processing of, your personal data). 

## Personal data we may collect about you

## Information that you provide

We will obtain personal information about you (such as your name, email address, phone number) whenever you complete forms on the Website. 

We will also obtain personal information you provide when you send us feedback, UPLOAD CONTENT, contact us for any reason and by any medium, share information via the website’s functions, report a problem with the website. 

We may ask you to provide sensitive personal data from time to time. If we request such data, we will give you additional information as to why we are requesting the sensitive personal data and how we will use it. We may retain a record of any contact you make with us. 

## Information that we will collect automatically

**Cookies:** We may monitor your use of the Website through the use of cookies and similar tracking devices. For example, we may monitor how many times you use the Website, which pages you go to and traffic data. This information helps us to build a profile of our users. Some of this data will be aggregated or statistical, which means that we will not be able to identify you individually. For further information on our use of cookies, please see the sections on cookies below.

**Device information:** We may also collect information about your device each time you use the Website. For example, we may collect information on the type of mobile device that you are using and its unique device identifier (for example, the IMEI number, the device’s mobile phone number, or the MAC address of the device’s wireless network interface), the type of mobile browser that you are using, the mobile operating system that you are using, mobile network information and the time zone setting.

**Information on your device:** We may also collect information which is stored on your device each time you use the Website. For example, we may collect contact information, login information, photos, videos and other digital content with your prior consent.

**Location data:** We may also collect information to determine your location using GPS technology or such other location tracking software we may use from time to time. Some of the features of the Website will require access to such location data to work. If you would like to use any such feature, you will be asked to consent to provide such location information. You can withdraw your consent to providing this information at any time by contacting us via contact@smooci.com.

**Information from third parties:** Occasionally we may receive information about you from other sources (such as credit reference agencies), which we will add to the information we already hold about you in order to help us supply our services to you.

## How we use your personal data

We use your personal data for the following purposes:

  * To help us identify you and any accounts you hold with us;
  * Administration;
  * Research, statistical analysis and behavioural analysis;
  * Customer profiling and analysing your preferences;
  * Marketing (Please see 'Marketing and opting out' as set out below);
  * Fraud prevention and detection;
  * Billing and order fulfilment for purchases made through our website;
  * Credit scoring and credit checking—see 'Credit checking', below;
  * Customising the Website and its content to your particular preferences;
  * To notify you of any changes to the Website or to our services that may affect you; and
  * Improving our services.

## Marketing and opting out

If you have given permission, we may share your personal data with organisations who are our business partners and we or they may contact you (unless you have asked us or them not to do so) by mail, telephone, sms, text/picture/video message, email, about products, services, promotions, special offers, charitable causes that may be of interest to you. If you prefer not to receive any further direct marketing communications from us or our business partners, you can opt out at any time. See further 'Your rights', below.

The Website may contain links to other websites or apps which we or our partners own, or websites or apps of our partners or third parties. Please note that if you follow any of these links, the websites, apps and services provided through them will have their own privacy policies/terms of use. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for their respective privacy policies/terms of use or the collection and use of any personal data collected through these websites, apps or services. Please ensure that you review the relevant privacy policies/terms of use prior to providing any personal data to, or using these websites, apps and services.

## Disclosure of your personal data

We may disclose your personal data to:

  * Other companies within our group;
  * A third party who acquires SMO-Tech or acquires substantially all of its assets, in which case the personal data shall be one of the acquired assets;
  * Our agents and service providers;
  * Law enforcement and regulatory agencies in connection with any investigation to help prevent unlawful activity or as otherwise required by applicable law;
  * Our business partners in accordance with the 'Marketing and opting out' section above.

## Keeping your data secure

We will use technical and organisational measures to safeguard your personal data, for example:

  * Access to your account is controlled by a password and username that are unique to you;
  * We store your personal data on secure servers;
  * Payment details are encrypted using SSL technology.

While we will use all reasonable efforts to safeguard your personal data, you acknowledge that the use of the internet is not entirely secure and for this reason we cannot guarantee the security or integrity of any personal data that are transferred from you or to you via the internet.

## Monitoring

We may monitor and record communications with you (such as telephone conversations and emails) for the purpose of quality assurance, training, fraud prevention and compliance.

## Information about other individuals

If you give us information on behalf of someone else, you confirm that the other person has appointed you to act on his/her behalf and has agreed that you can:

  * Give consent on his/her behalf to the processing of his/her personal data;
  * Receive on his/her behalf any data protection notices; and
  * Give consent to the transfer of his/her personal data abroad.

## Your rights

You have the right, subject to the payment of a small fee (currently £10), to request access to personal data that we may process about you. If you wish to exercise this right, you should:

  * Put your request in writing;
  * Include proof of your identity and address (eg a copy of your driving licence or passport, and a recent utility or credit card bill);
  * Attach a cheque in the amount of £10 made payable to SMO-Tech; and
  * Specify the personal data you want access to, including any account or reference numbers where applicable.

You have the right to require us to correct any inaccuracies in your data free of charge. If you wish to exercise this right, you should:

  * Put your request in writing;
  * Provide us with enough information to identify you; and
  * Specify the information that is incorrect and what it should be replaced with.

You also have the right to ask us to stop processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. If you wish to exercise this right, you should:

  * Put your request in writing (an email sent to contact@smooci.com with a header that says 'Unsubscribe' is acceptable); and
  * Provide us with enough information to identify you, and
  * If your objection is not to direct marketing in general, but to direct marketing by a particular channel (eg email or telephone), please specify the channel you are objecting to.

## Use of cookies

A cookie is a small text file which is placed onto your mobile (or other electronic device) when you access our Website. We use cookies and other online tracking devices on our Website to:

  * Keep track of the items stored in your shopping basket and take you through the checkout process; 
  * Recognise you whenever you visit the Website (this speeds up your access to the Website as you do not have to log on each time);
  * Obtain information about your preferences, online movements and use of the internet;
  * Carry out research and statistical analysis to help improve our content, products and services and to help us better understand our visitor and customer requirements and interests;
  * Target our marketing and advertising campaigns and those of our partners more effectively by providing interest-based advertisements that are personalised to your interests; and
  * Make your online experience more efficient and enjoyable.

The information we obtain from our use of cookies will not usually contain your personal data. Although we may obtain information about your device such as your IP address, your browser and/or other internet log information, this will not usually identify you personally.In certain circumstances we may collect personal information about you—but only where you voluntarily provide it (eg by completing an online form) or where you purchase goods or services from us.

In most cases we will need your consent in order to use cookies on this Website. The exception is where the cookie is essential in order for us to provide you with a service you have requested (eg to enable you to put items in your shopping basket and use our check-out process).

## Consent (browser settings)

If you visit our Website when your browser is set to accept cookies, we will interpret this as an indication that you consent to our use of cookies and other similar technologies as described in this website cookie policy. If you change your mind in the future about letting us use cookies, you can modify the settings of your browser to reject cookies or disable cookies completely.

## Consent (notification on home page)

There is a notice on our home page which describes how we use cookies and which also provides a link to our Website privacy policy. If you use this website after this notification has been displayed to you, we will assume that you consent to our use of cookies for the purposes described in this Website privacy policy.

## Third party cookies

We work with third-party suppliers who may also set cookies on our Website, for example Google. These third-party suppliers are responsible for the cookies they set on our site. If you want further information please go to the website for the relevant third party. You will find additional information in the table below.

## Description of cookies

The table below is designed to provide more information about the cookies we use and why:

Name of cookie | Owner | Purpose of the cookie  
---|---|---  
Google Analytics – _ga, _gat, __utma, __utmt, __utmb, __utmc, __utmz, __utmv | GOOGLE INC. | This is a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. which uses cookies to show us how visitors found and explored our site, and how we can enhance their experience. It provides us with information about the behaviour of our visitors (eg how long they stayed on the site, the average number of pages viewed) and also tells us how many visitors we have had.)  
  
## How to turn off cookies

If you do not want to accept cookies, you can change your browser settings so that cookies are not accepted. If you do this, please be aware that you may lose some of the functionality of the Website. For further information about cookies and how to disable them please go to: www.aboutcookies.org or www.allaboutcookies.org.

## Changes to this privacy policy

We may change this Policy from time to time. You should check this policy frequently to ensure you are aware of the most recent version that will apply each time you use the Website.

Last updated 17 August 2017.
